aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com

832-651-1700

Objective

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience managing iOS mobile applications from front-end to backend, start to finish. An adaptable, goal-oriented, team player who is self sufficient and motivated to finding reliable solutions to new problems.

- Swift 4.0 / Java / Python / SQL / PostgreSQL / Django / Flask / Zendesk / JIRA / Taiga / RESTful APIs / MongoDB / Docker / Matplotlib / Scikit-learn / Gevent / Circus / Nginx / Git Control / UIKit
- SDKs (iOS and Android): Fabric / Stripe / Google Maps / Alamofire / TRON / SwiftyJSON / Facebook / Twitter / Firebase / Parse / Twilio / Charts / GSON / Picasso / Retrofit / EventBus

Experience

Lead Mobile Engineer; Croozen LLC, Houston,TX — 10/2017- 1/2017 - Contract

Oversee iOS development, UX/UI and ARC Memory Project.

- Execute MVC patterns and developed practical modeling schemas.
- Created backend API with python.
- Location-based app design.
- Data persistence through Core Data, Caching and File management, MongoDB.
- Redesigned User Interface with incorporated features such as, Safety nuances, Checkpoint initiations, etc. .

aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com

832-651-1700

Lead Software Engineer; InteractiveTel LLC, Houston,TX — 12/2016-12/2017 - Commercial/Permanent

Oversee iOS and Android creations, functionalities and interactions. Work with a team to push integrated features to production.

- Execute MVC patterns and developed practical modeling schemas.
- Created various API's, notifications and data models.
- Engineered app functionality to coincide with speech recognition.
- Tested data transmission through BLE connections.
- Created white noise filters for communication clarity.
- Applied Sql techniques and database modeling.
- Leveraged data persistence through Core Data, Caching and File management.
- Analyze data and make custom reports using scripts.
- Managed two admin. apps as well as two consumer apps.
- Created multiple Python backend servers and scripts using Pycharm

Mobile App Developer; Candorson LLC, Houston,TX — 06/23/2014-09/25/2016 - Commercial/Permanent

Work with a team of developers to complete mobile applications from the initial stages to the finished product. Proficient in wireframes, Sketch and MVC techniques to efficiently complete work in a prompt manner.

Problem solver and detailed oriented.

Projects consist of but not limited to:

Bubble Bazooka(iOS game)

Postablur(Social Media)

aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com

832-651-1700

Koncrete(Shopping)

Mattress One (Interactive Training)

TForce Security(CMS)

Languages include:

Xcode (Swift)

PHP

Android Studio (Java)

SQL

VMS QA/QC Systems Assistant, Cenergy International; Houston,TX — 03/2014-12/2015

Supervised and assisted on managing the Inspections of Maintenance Program, HSE Program, Drug and Alcohol Program, Inspections and Assisted in managing quality assurance and quality control (QA/QC) to all customer units under the QA/QC Project and Systems Manager.

- Maintain system efficiency, standards and data centers
- Perform daily systems monitoring and backup operations
- Test Systems and aid in implementations
- Research and apply data models
- Authorized payments and report delinquent accounts
- Create and remove user accounts
- Aid in creating codes and system queries
- Supervise Audits

<u>aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com</u>

832-651-1700

Education

Stephen F Austin State University, Nacogdoches, TX - BS in I/O Psychology 2014

Leadership

Member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Incorporated – Vice President

Member of Alpha Phi Omega Fraternity - Member

Neuroscience Lab Assistant - Undergrad

UX Team Lead- Postablur

Team Lead- Mattress One Mobile App Development

References

(Upon request)